Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
What are you so angry about?
（カルタフィルス）
何を そんなに怒ってるの？
（ユリシィ）あっ… おい！
Hey!
Hey, mage!
おい！ 魔法使い
I'm sorry for getting in the way of your experiment,
（カルタフィルス）
実験を邪魔したのは悪かったけど
人間なんて
君にとっては 十把ひとからげ
but humans are a dime a
dozen as far as you're concerned.
I thought they were worthless to you.
取るに足らないもの
じゃなかったのかい？
You can just take a quick look
around and snatch one right up. Easy.
ちょちょっと探して
ちゃちゃっとさらって
くればいいじゃない
Right?
How rude! I was still talking.
ひどいじゃないか
まだ しゃべってるのに
Come on, you!
（ユリシィ）おい！ お前…
イザベル…
Isabelle...
Where am I?
（チセ）
ここは…
Isabelle, did they tease you again?
（ユリシィ）
イザベル
また 何か からかわれたのか？
It's that man's voice.
（チセ）
あのヒトの声だ…
This is the appearance that God gave me.
（イザベル）
神様にもらった姿なのに
It's not like I can help that my hair is carrot-colored,
髪が ニンジン色なのも
瞳が 雑草色なのも
or that my eyes are the color of weeds.
全部 私には どうしようもないもの
ワン！
I love you no matter what you look like.
（ユリシィ）
俺は お前が どんな形だって
好きだぞ
Cheer up.
元気を出せ！
Let's see....
え〜っと…
Ulysse?
ユリシィ？
Thanks, Ulysse!
ありがとう ユリシィ
Isabelle!
（ユリシィ）
イザベル！
What happened, Isabelle?
イザベル どうした？
A child got hit by a carriage!
（女性）
子供が馬車に はねられたわ！
（ユリシィのほえ声）
（男性）こいつは ひでえ！
This is bad!
I saw them chasing after Isabelle!
（女の子）
あいつらがイザベルを
追いかけてたのを見たわ！
I-It's not our fault!
（男の子）
ぼ… 僕たちのせいじゃないよ！
こいつが勝手に道に…
She ran into the street herself!
Wait.
（ユリシィ）
待って
Wait, please!
待ってくれ
When is Isabelle waking up?
イザベルは いつ起きるんだ？
I haven't heard her voice in a long time.
もう ずっと 声を聞いてない
イザベル
Isabelle.
Isabelle!
イザベル？
イザベル！
Ulysse, Isabelle is gone.
（イザベルの父）ユリシィ
もう イザベルは
逝ってしまったんだよ
She's just sleeping.
（ユリシィ）
まだ眠っているだけだ
We're going home.
（イザベルの父）家に帰るんだ
No.
（ユリシィ）
いいや！ いいや 親父(おやじ)殿
No, Father.
I'm waiting here.
俺は ここで待つんだ
She's going to be lonely if she wakes up alone.
イザベルが起きたときに
１人じゃ寂しいだろうから
Always.
いつも… いつまでも
Forever.
It's all right.
大丈夫
I woke up, didn't I?
私は起きたでしょ？
チセ…
Chise...
Elias.
（チセ）エリアス！
（カルタフィルス）あ〜あ
Aww... Her materials cost quite a bit, you know.
結構 材料費かかったんだよ？
その子
Corpses aren't free, nor is managing the containers.
死体を買うのも
培養槽の管理もタダじゃ…
Cartaphilus.
（エリアス）カルタフィルス…
Don't you dare call me by that name.
（カルタフィルス）その名前で…
僕を呼ぶな
You're just a monster that found a human body.
ヒトの肉を得た…
化け物の分際で
（チセ）エリアス！
Elias!
A freak calling another a freak, huh?
（レンフレッド）
化け物が 他者を化け物呼ばわりか
笑わせる
What a joke.
（レンフレッド）
弾には 肉体の再生を止める魔術を
仕込んだが…
I've put a spell on the bullet to stop regeneration.
Chise, you're alive...
（エリアス）チセ… 生きて…
Looks like it works.
（レンフレッド）
問題ないようだな
I'm in a bit...
ちょっと…
Well, I'm in a lot of pain.
いや だいぶ痛いですけど
まあ 何とか
But I made it.
I'm surprised.
（エリアス）おどろ… いた
I'm a little surprised, too.
（チセ）私も ちょっと驚きました
（エリアス）チセ
Chise, am I not terrifying in this form?
この姿は怖いだろ？
I'm going to turn back, so let go.
戻るから 離しな
You're right.
（チセ）そうですね
I don't think you could get
through the door being that tall.
家の扉が くぐれなさそうで
不便だから
You should probably turn back.
戻ったほうがよさそうです
（エリアス）そう… だね
You're right...
Silky would be furious with me if I broke the door.
（エリアス）
扉を壊しでもしたら
シルキーに怒られそうだ
I'd apologize with you even if she was.
もし 怒られても
一緒に謝りますけど
That's reassuring.
（エリアス）それは 心強いね
ハア…
This girl has strange taste.
（レンフレッド）
物好きな子だ
Master!
アリス
Alice.
Master...
師匠…
（アリス）ふごっ！
（レンフレッド）このバカ！
You idiot!
Don't go darting off like that!
（レンフレッド）
１人で 確認もせず突っ走るな！
I thought about abandoning you when I saw your letter.
書き置きだけ見つけたときには
見捨てようかと思っただろうが！
I'm sorry.
（アリス）ごべんなざい…
Don't overestimate your own strength.
（レンフレッド）
自分の力を過信するな
少しは考えろ
Think about it.
（アリス）でも！
But!
でも…
But...
You wouldn't have...
そしたら 師匠が…
（レンフレッド）ハア…
You're my apprentice and my bodyguard.
お前は私の弟子で 護(まも)り手だ
A bodyguard ought not to leave their master's side.
護り手が主人のそばを離れるな
Yes, sir.
はい！
You're awful.
（カルタフィルス）ひどいなあ
The brain's complicated.
脳はさ
It takes a lot of work to fix.
複雑だから
直すのが大変なんだよ？
You...
（レンフレッド）貴様…
（カルタフィルス）
僕は ただ いい素材として
そこの犬が欲しいだけなんだけど
I just want that dog because he'd make a good subject.
Sorcerers don't step into mage territory.
（レンフレッド）
魔術師は
魔法使いの領分には踏み入らない
暗黙の了解だったはずだ
That was a tacit agreement.
Why do you go after the fairies?
なぜ 貴様は 妖精に手を出す？
Because it seems fun.
（カルタフィルス）
だって 面白そうじゃないか
I could make something
interesting if I used a fairy for a chimera.
キメラの中身に妖精を使ったら
とても便利なものが
造れそうなんだもの
But fairy curses are a pain to deal with.
だけど 妖精の呪いは面倒だからさ
そこの魔術師に首輪つけたのに
That's why I put a collar on that sorcerer.
You monster.
怪物め
I don't need a dog if it can't even run my errands.
お使いもできない犬なら
いらないや
それ…
Isn't...
that...
Isabelle?
イザベル…
That isn't your Isabelle.
（チセ）
あれは
あなたのイザベルじゃないよ
I've seen you before.
あなた 前にも見たことある
You deceived Matthew in Ulthar and killed Mina.
ウルタールでマシューをだまして
ミナを殺したヤツ
Ulthar?
ウルタール？
Oh, the cat experiment.
ああ 猫実験か
I think I could get some decent results if I tried it again.
もう一度やったら
今度は それなりの結果になると
思うんだけど
どうかな？
What do you think?
Chise.
（エリアス）チセ？
You won't have him.
（チセ）渡さない
I absolutely won't let you have him!
この子は…
絶対に 渡さない！
生意気なガキだなあ
What an annoying brat.
チセ…
Chise...
Anything?
何でも？
Yup.
（エリアス）そう
魔法というのはね
Truth be told, you can do anything with magic.
実を言うと やろうと思えば
何だってできるんだよ
You can turn rocks into gold,
石ころを金(きん)に変えること
魚を空に泳がせること
make fish swim through the sky,
keep harvests from ever rotting.
作物を腐らせず
そのままでいさせることも
His words fly through my mind.
（チセ）
彼の言葉が頭の中で滑っていく
But... that's something that must not be done.
（エリアス）
でもね
それは してはいけないことなんだ
I won't let you have him.
あなたには 渡さない
へえ ガキのくせに物知りだね
You're pretty knowledgeable for a kid.
Tarantula hawks.
ベッコウバチ… 蜘蛛(くも)の天敵だ
They prey on spiders.
But being so small,
でも そんな小ささじゃあ
they're just going to get eaten.
逆に食べられちゃうよ？
Chise, stop this!
（エリアス）チセ！ やめるんだ
君の体が…
Your body is...
（エリアス）うっ…
（ユリシィ）魔法使い！
Mage!
She just ate a little of me.
（エリアス）少し喰(く)われただけだ
チセ！
Chise!
（エリアス）チセ！
Chise, you mustn't do that.
チセ それはいけない
僕らは世界のルールを
ねじ曲げてはいけないんだ
We must not twist the rules of this world!
Horse and Hattock!
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
ホース･アンド･ハトック！
A fairy spell, huh?
（カルタフィルス）妖精の呪文か…
Not bad.
やってくれるね
Why did I want that, again?
（カルタフィルス）
なんで あれが欲しいんだっけ？
To make a chimera.
キメラを造るのに
そもそも なんで僕は キメラを？
必要性は？
Why did I want to make a chimera in the first place?
For what purpose?
Oh, whatever.
まあ 何でもいいや
Now, go find him with your strings.
さあ お前の糸で捜しておくれ
That wretch won't come looking for us here.
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
ここら辺なら
あの野郎も追ってこないだろうよ
Thank you, Blue Flame.
（エリアス）助かったよ 青い火
The Thorn of Shadows?
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
影の茨(いばら)かよ
たく…
やっかい事 持ち込みやがってよ
Damn it, you've brought so much trouble with you.
Buy you don't hate it, do you?
（エリアス）嫌いじゃないだろ？
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）まあね
（アリス）頭に乗るな！
Not really.
Get off my head!
He's a Will-o'-the-Wisp.
（エリアス）
彼は ウィル･オー･ウィスプ
A blue flame fairy that lives in forests
and cemeteries, confusing passers-by.
墓や森に棲(す)んで人を惑わす
青い鬼火の妖精だ
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
呼び名は やめろ！ マナー違反だぞ
Don't say my name!
That's rude!
Fine, fine.
（チセ）ハア… ハア…
My blood's racing through my body.
（チセ）
全身の血が
すごい速度で巡っている
Chise, calm down.
（エリアス）
チセ 落ち着いて　大丈夫だから
It'll be all right.
Elias.
（チセ）エリアス… エリアス…
ごめんなさい… ごめんなさい…
I'm sorry.
I didn't listen to you.
言いつけを… ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
（エリアス）次から 気をつけて
Be careful from now on.
That's good enough.
それでいい
（チセ）スーハー スーハー
（チセ）うっ…
（ユリシィ）チセ！
Chise!
（チセ）ハア… ハア…
It feels like my blood's going to overflow and explode.
（チセ）
体の血が あふれて
パンクしそう
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
お前が夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)か
You're a Sleigh Beggy, huh?
ひ弱だな かわいそうに
You're so weak.
Poor thing.
Take my coal.
俺の石炭を持っとけよ
You'll feel a little better.
少しは楽になるだろ
It's warm.
（チセ）
あったかい…
You're finally awake, you sleepy dog.
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
お前は やっとこさ 目が覚めたか
ねぼすけ犬(いぬ)
I'm not a dog!
犬じゃない！ 俺は…
I'm...
Don't be crazy, you dumb dog.
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
とっ散らかったこと
言ってんじゃねえよ バカ犬
おめえは人間でもねえし
ただの犬っころでもねえ
You're neither human, nor an ordinary dog.
まだ 寝ぼけてんのかよ！
Are you still not awake?
Grow up, puppy,
いつまで 子犬のまんま
死んじまったヤツに甘えてんだ！
and stop depending on dead people!
Quit whining and go back to
your useful form, church grim!
ピーピー泣いてないで
さっさと役目を果たす格好に戻れ
墓守犬(チャーチ･グリム)！
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
おめえは墓荒らしのケツを
地獄の門まで追っかけ回す…
Your job is to chase the grave
robbers' asses to the gates of Hell.
You're a black dog.
黒妖犬(ブラック･ドッグ)だろうが
I see.
（ユリシィ）
そうか… そうだったんだな
That's what it was.
I get it now.
今なら 分かる
No matter how long I wait, my sister won't come back.
どれだけ待っても
俺の妹は もう… 戻らない
Chise, will you take me with you?
（ユリシィ）チセ
俺を お前のそばへ
連れていってくれないか？
I'll give you my all.
全てを お前にやるから
You're one thick-headed dog!
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
バッカな犬だな！ お前は
スレイ･ベガとはいえ
Sleigh Beggy or not, we can't be the
ones to ask a human to make a pact!
わざわざ 俺たちから
人間に結びを求めるなんて！
A pact?
結び？
He's requesting to become your familiar.
（エリアス）
使い魔になるという申し入れだ
The ultimate promise, that you
would share everything with one another.
その中でも 全てを共有するという
何よりも強い約束
Your senses, your emotions, even your time.
感覚 感情 時間さえもね
Time?
（チセ）時間？
If you die, he dies.
（エリアス）君が死ねば 彼も死ぬ
そんなの！
No!
It's fine.
（ユリシィ）いいんだ
I've seen inside you, so I know.
俺も お前を視(み)たから知ってる
Don't you need to wait for Isabelle?
（チセ）イザベルは…
待たなくていいの？
There you guys are.
（カルタフィルス）
あっ！ こんな所にいた
カルタフィルス！
Cartaphilus!
I told you not to call me that!
その名前を…
呼ぶなって言ってるだろ！
You're so mean.
（カルタフィルス）ひどいなあ
I'd gotten used to that arm. How inconvenient.
使い慣れた腕がなくなると
不便なのに
I won't give your arm back.
君の腕 返してあげないよ？
I don't want an arm that's been
used as an ingredient for a freak.
怪物の材料に成り果てた腕など
こちらから願い下げだ
Hey, he's taken on a dog's form.
あっ 犬のカタチになってる
That makes him an easier target.
狙いやすいな
Please, Chise.
（ユリシィ）頼む！ チセ
If you die, he dies.
（エリアス）
君も死ねば 彼も死ぬ
I don't want him to take me.
（ユリシィ）
あいつに からめとられるより
ここにいるより
I don't want to be here.
I'd rather be your...
俺は お前の…
It's okay.
（チセ）大丈夫
I don't want to be alone anymore, either.
もう独りになりたくないのは
私も同じだから
Continue after me.
俺に続いて言葉を
Tie now the silver thread.
いざや 結べ 銀の緒を
Tie now the roots of our veins.
いざや 繋(つな)げ 血潮の根
The holly, so that we may not be separated.
離れぬように ヒイラギを
The ivy, so that we may not come apart.
ほどけぬように キヅタを
Tie to the yew tree seven times.
（２人）七つのイチイに 七度(たび)結べ
Until the day the snake spits out its tail.
果ての蛇が尾を吐く日まで
Chise, give me a new name.
チセ
俺に新しい名前をくれ
Take me by your side.
俺を
お前のそばに連れていってくれ
おいで
Come,
Ruth.
“ルツ”
（カルタフィルス）おお… あらら
Oh, dear.
He woke up from his dream of being human.
ヒトの夢から覚めちゃったのか
Good night, Isabelle.
（ルツ）おやすみ イザベル
Wait for me until my time with her is over.
（ルツ）
俺とあの子の時が終わるまで
待っててくれ
（カルタフィルス）
な〜んだ
その子のモノになっちゃったのか
Too bad.
So you belong to her now, huh?
Undoing a pact is such a pain.
結びを解くのは面倒だなあ
Why don't you back off, then?
（レンフレッド）
面倒なら 手を引けばどうだ？
Yeah.
うん そうする
I will.
What's with that look?
なあに？ その顔
You learn to give up quickly
when you live for a long time.
長いこと生きてると
諦めも早くなるもんだよ？
What is the purpose that drives you?
（レンフレッド）
貴様は何が目的で動いてる？
To live without suffering.
（カルタフィルス）
苦しみなく生きるため
I'm sick of rotting away until an
end that I don't even know will come.
いつ来るか分からない
終わりの日まで
朽ちたままは嫌だもの
It hurts.
痛くて 苦しい…
It's painful.
Huh?
あれ？
But why is my body like this?
でも なんで 僕は こんな体に…
You don't mind making others suffer for your sake?
（レンフレッド）
ならば 自分のために
他人が苦しんでもいいというのか？
That's right.
そうだよ
Isn't that how living things are?
そういうものでしょ？
生き物ってさ
（エリアス）
そう思うのなら
君は人間でも ケダモノでもない
If that's what you think, you're neither human nor beast.
You're nothing but a monster
in human form, Cartaphilus.
ヒトの形をした怪物でしかないよ
カルタフィルス
My name is Joseph, little boy.
僕の名前はヨセフだよ おチビさん
See you around.
またね
He's like a natural disaster.
（レンフレッド）
天災のようなヤツだな
At least disasters are knowable.
（エリアス）
得体が知れてる分
災害のほうがタチがいいよ
Cartaphilus...
（レンフレッド）カルタフィルス…
It's said that the Son of God
cursed him so that he can never die.
はるか昔
神の息子に死ねない呪いを
かけられたといわれている男
He's a monster that roams aimlessly,
driven only to satiate his curiosity.
目的も はっきりせず
ただ ひたすら
自分の興味だけで動く怪物だ
And what happened was the
result of being chosen by that monster.
（エリアス）
で… 怪物に目を付けられた結果が
それか
（レンフレッド）ハア…
Just why?
（エリアス）何だって また？
My head may have flown if I'd refused.
（レンフレッド）
断ったら
首が飛びかねない状況だったから
I had no choice.
しかたなくだ
I see.
（エリアス）なるほどね
（レンフレッド）おい 貴様
You.
Have you met him before?
あいつと会ったことはあるか？
Him?
（エリアス）あれと？
No way.
ないよ そんなの
（レンフレッド）そうか
I see.
（エリアス）
帰るなら 気をつけろよ
Be careful on your way home.
I don't need you to worry for me.
（レンフレッド）
貴様に心配されるいわれはない
We're going.
（レンフレッド）帰るぞ
（アリス）はい！
Okay!
Now, then.
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）さてと…
I have to send them off.
俺は こいつを
あっちまで送ってやんなきゃな
You sure are a hard worker.
（エリアス）仕事熱心だな
（ウィル･オー･ウィスプ）
生きたヤツは沼に ご案内すんのが
俺の仕事だけど
My job is to send the living to the swamp.
But my job is also to see the
dead off to the gates to the other side.
死んだヤツは
あっちの門まで ご案内ってのも
俺の仕事さ
This one is artificial, but
being so, it'll bear an artificial soul.
こいつは作り物(もん)だけど
作り物には 作り物の魂
ってのが宿るわな
See you!
じゃあな
Well, we'd better head home, too.
（エリアス）
じゃ 僕たちも 帰ろうか
説明だの何だのは 明日にしよう
I can explain things to you tomorrow.
You must be tired.
疲れたでしょ？
（チセ）はい
Yes.
Your scolding will come when we get home, too.
（エリアス）小言も帰ってからね
Okay.
（チセ）はい…
ルツ？
Ruth.
Let's go home together, Ruth.
一緒に帰ろう ルツ
Yeah.
From now on, where you go home is where I go home.
お前の帰る所が
これからは 俺の帰る所だ
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
A new friend.
（チセ）
新しい友
つかの間 訪れた 穏やかな休息
A brief, peaceful rest.
The girl steps into a beautiful rose garden,
her mind still burdened by her troubles.
少女は心に陰りを抱えたまま
美しいバラ園へと 足を踏み入れる
Speak of me, and I'll eat you.
（リャナン･シー）
私のこと 口に出したら
食べちゃうからね